https://devdilip-aboutme.netlify.com/



bit.ly/devDilip

LINKEDIN: bit.ly/linkDilip

SKILLS

TECHNOLOGY:

Javascript(ES6) React / redux NodeJS

HTML5

CSS3

Express REST APIs

Postgres SQL

Sequelize

Bootstrap

Material UI

Git, Github, CMD

Docker

Jest

TypeScript

BUSINESS:

UX

UI Design

Wireframing

DigitalMarketing

GoogleAnalytics

FB Ads

Google Ads

User Research

CONTACT

dilip.singh@iiml.org 0633030215 Rotterdam

Visa -'TWV niet vereist'

PROFILE

After working for more than 4 years solving Business challenges, I completed accelerated boot-camp to switch career to align with my enthusiasm for technology. Now, my focus is to use that knowledge to make useful and high quality applications that help solve problems. I am looking for a role as web developer for a company that provides a mix of challenge and opportunity. I am a conceptual thinker with ability to break down a complex problem. This belief was helped by me winning the HERE Technologies Hackathon held in Eindhoven in June 2019 where we came up with winning solution for a real world problem

WORK EXPERIENCE

Codaisseur - Full stack Developer Trainee

Invoice/Warranty manager

A full stack application that is an online Warranty management application to keep your appliance Invoices/warranties safe and get custom notifications about their expiration using React, Express, Postgres, REST API, Bootstrap, nodemailer, Docker, JWT

Lab Book

A Full stack application to help people working in a Laboratory. User can keep track of experiments progress and record keeping also, with an option to note ideas and a todo list in a separate section. Built using React, Express, Material UI, REST APIs

Ticket swapping platform

An online platform where user can create account to create events, add tickets and comments. It also uses an algorithm to check the risk per ticket. Built using React, Express, Postgres, REST API, Bootstrap, Docker, JWT

Times Internet - Project Manager

February 2017 - May 2018

- Analytics: Improved content discovery through Google-analytics & users feedback for OTT App. Result: Improved average session duration (time/visit) by 50% through improvement to design over 6 months
- E-commerce: Established the e-commerce platform by tying up with vendors and implemented selling platform on app and website (Shopify) with the help of digital marketing (Google/FB). Result: Getting sales from the first month of the launch with 100% MoM increase for six months with total sales of INR 1,000,000

ICICI Bank - Wealth Manager

February 2015 - February 2017

• Managed key accounts for the bank handling their investment portfolios. Gathered financial requirements and devised asset allocation plans. Result: Generated highest revenue for 2 consecutive quarters for the bank in North Zone and meeting annual targets. Felicitated as top performer for various bank product categories

Newgen Software - Business Analyst

December 2013 - February 2015

· Managed key accounts for IT company by implementing the software on gathered client requirements. Result: Identified additional requirements that helped clients with meeting special needs and generated 30% extra revenue for my company

EDUCATION

CODAISSEUR BOOTCAMP

Full-stack Web development course following AGILE Methodology (Jan - Mar 2020)

IIM LUCKNOW

Masters in Business Administration (June 2011 - Feb 2013)

PEC. CHANDIGARH

Bachelors in Computer Science Engineering (June 2006 - June 2010)